<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
  <title>hypomnema</title>
  <link href='http://www.hypomnema.net/'/>
  <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:09Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Thomas Lee Culverwell</name>
  </author>
  <id>http://hypomnema.net/</id>
    <entry>
    <title>Spinning tops</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/spinning-tops'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/spinning-tops</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:09Z</updated>
    <summary>System monitoring is useful whether on a home desktop, workstation, or
server. The classic Unix program top defines the standard interface: an
interactive, filterable, running tally of what is hogging how many
resources. But in the decades since release, top faces increasing
competition:</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/spinning-tops'></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A hop, skip, and a jump</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/a-hop-skip-and-a-jump'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/a-hop-skip-and-a-jump</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:09Z</updated>
    <summary>There’s many benefits to working from the command line. A
terminal-centric workflow is broadly cross-platform, uses less system
resources, is highly customizable, and most importantly fast. But only
if you take a little time to get acquainted with the right tools. Take
the example of moving up, down, and around the filesystem hierarchy:</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/a-hop-skip-and-a-jump'></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>One small step for man</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/one-small-step-for-man'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/one-small-step-for-man</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:08Z</updated>
    <summary>‘Read the manual’—timeless and sage advice. But what about a summary?
Can one hundred words be more useful than twenty thousand? Enough
developers think so to write several alternatives to the classic Unix
man and GNU info systems. A quick test lookup of documentation for gpg
brought surprising results:</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/one-small-step-for-man'></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rusting tools</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/rusting-tools'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/rusting-tools</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:08Z</updated>
    <summary>There are many classic command line tools known for their gotchas. The
flags for some are famously cryptic, and arcana rest buried in the heart
of Unix. A few Rust developers have decided to refresh the scene with
new attempts at solving these epoch-old problems. These new tools are
not likely to displace programs that have decades of use in production
behind them, but they can make working in the terminal far more
ergonomic:</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/rusting-tools'></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dead reckoning</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/dead-reckoning'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/dead-reckoning</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:08Z</updated>
    <summary>  The happiest changes that have happened among the nations have usually
  been bought by bloody catastrophes of which innocence was the victim.</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/dead-reckoning'></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If you like your app, you can keep it!</title>
    <link href='https://hypomnema.net/if-you-like-your-app'/>
    <id>https://hypomnema.net/if-you-like-your-app</id>
    <updated>2020-04-22T20:24:09Z</updated>
    <summary>  Democracy is, by the nature of it, a self-canceling business; and it
  gives in the long run a net result of zero.</summary>
    <content type='html' src='https://hypomnema.net/if-you-like-your-app'></content>
  </entry>
</feed>
